Emanuele Sansone

Email: e.sansone@hotmail.it Website: http://emsansone.github.io/ GitHub: https://github.com/emsansone

Summary

Researcher in the field of machine learning and artificial intelligence. I worked on unsupervised and representation learning. Along with research, I share a passion for the world of sport. I am an experienced ski instructor with international ski racing background.

Education

2013-2018 Ph.D.

ICT doctoral school, University of Trento, Italy

Thesis: "Towards Uncovering the True Use of Unlabeled Data in Machine Learning"

Advisor: Prof. Francesco G.B. De Natale.

Dissertation in multiple areas of machine learning, including semi-supervised, positive unlabeled and unsupervised representation learning.

2011-2012

M.Sc. in Telecommunications Engineering

University of Trento, Italy

Thesis: "Multimodal Photo Galleries Synchronization"

Advisor: Prof. Nicola Conci, Giulia Boato. 110/110 summa cum laude | Gpa: 28.82/30

Computer vision application for automatic synchronization of photo galleries from multiple users attending

the same event (C++ language).

2008-2010

B.Sc. in Telecommunications Engineering

University of Trento, Italy

Thesis: "Master P-NET protocol implementation on PIC 32 architecture"

Advisor: Prof. Dario Petri, Eng. Michele Corrà.

Programming a master device in a network composed by different sensors and actuators. Implementation of

P-NET protocol over a PIC 32 microcontroller (C language).

Work Professional Experience

2018-2020

Research Scientist

Huawei Technologies R&D, London, UK

Working in the area of deep generative models and self-supervised learning. Mentoring intern students.

2018-to date

Reviewer

Serving as a reviewer for international journals in the area of machine learning and signal processing, such as IEEE Transactions of Neural Networks and Learning Systems, Machine Learning (Springer) and IEEE Transactions on Image Processing.

Academic Experience

2016 Teaching Assistant, Computer Vision (Code 140266)

M.Sc. in Telecommunications Engineering, University of Trento, Italy

Machine Learning for Computer Vision (introduction to statistical learning theory and neural networks).

2015 Teaching Assistant, Multimedia Networking (Code 140151)

M.Sc. in Telecommunications Engineering, University of Trento, Italy

Principles of video compression/coding (useful for transmission/storage of video files).

2015-2016 Research Intern

LAMDA group, Nanjing University, China

Advisor: Prof. Zhi-Hua Zhou.

Working on positive unlabeled learning.

Sport Professional Experience

2011-to date Ski master instructor

Italy

Holding several professional education and training courses for ski instructors and candidate ski instructors. This is the highest professional degree in alpine skiing (the total number of ski master instructors in Italy is around 200).

2007-2017 Ski coach

Italy

Coach of young athletes (6-20 years old) in several racing ski teams: Ski Team Sopramonte (2007/2008), Sci Club Padova (2008/2009), Sci Club Panarotta (2009-2011), Ski Team Paganella (2013/2014), Campiglio Ski Team (2016/2017).

2002-2007 Ski athlete

Italy

See a sample list of records.

Awards and Certificates

2020 Algorithms Specialization

Certificate of completion

Organization: Coursera (Stanford University)

2018 Full Stack Deep Learning Bootcamp

Berkeley, USA

Certificate of completion

Organization: University of California, Berkeley

2017 Neural Networks for Machine Learning

Certificate of completion

Organization: Coursera (University of Toronto)

2016 Academic Hardware Grant Award

Provision of a NVIDIA Titan X GPU
Organization: NVIDIA corporation

2015 Machine Learning Summer School

Austin, USA

Certificate of completion

Organization: University of Texas at Austin

2012 | Merit Award

Trento, Italy

Award assigned to distinguished students Organization: University of Trento

2011 Ski Master Instructor

Milan, Italy Certificate

Organization: FISI, CoScuMa

2011 Ski Coach (3° level)

Milan, Italy Certificate

Organization: FISI, STF

2007 Ski Instructor

Trento, Italy
Certificate
Organization: PAT

Invited Talks

2019 Coulomb Autoencoders

Symposium on Deep Generative Models, British Computer Society (London, UK)

2017 Generative Adversarial Networks

Fondazione Bruno Kessler (Trento, Italy)

Publications

2020 Coulomb Autoencoders

E. Sansone, H. T. Ali, J. Sun

To appear in European Conference on Artificial Intelligence (ECAI)

2018 Towards Uncovering the True Use of Unlabeled Data in Machine Learning

E. Sansone PhD Thesis

2018 Efficient Training for Positive Unlabeled Learning

E. Sansone, F.G.B De Natale, Z.H. Zhou

IEEE Transactions on Pattern Asnalysis and Machine Intelligence (TPAMI), Code

2017 Training Feedforward Neural Networks with Standard Logistic Activations is Feasible

E. Sansone, F.G.B. De Natale

arXiv pre-print

2017 Automatic Synchronization of Multi-User Photo Galleries

E. Sansone, K. Apostolidis, N. Conci, G. Boato, V. Mezaris, F.G.B. De Natale

IEEE Transactions on Multimedia (TMM), Code

2016 Classtering: Joint Classification and Clustering with Mixture of Factor Analysers

E. Sansone, A. Passerini, F.G.B. De Natale

European Conference on Artificial Intelligence (ECAI), Code

2014 Synchronizing Multi-User Photo Galleries with MRF

E. Sansone, G. Boato, MS. Dao

MediaEval Workshop

2013 Event Clustering and Classification from Social Media: Watershed-based and Kernel

Methods

TV. Nguyen, MS. Dao, R. Mattivi, E. Sansone, F.G.B. De Natale, G. Boato

MediaEval Workshop

Languages

Italian: Mothertongue
English: Fluent (C2)
German: Fluent (B2)

Other Interests

Volunteering From 2012 to 2014, I've participated to a no-profit association, GiPro, composed by young representatives

of different sectors (e.g. ski instructors, engineers, lawyers, psychologists). The goal of the association is to promote the professional categories on the territory and stimulate the inter-professional collaboration of young

people.

Others I like playing soccer and hiking.

References

Francesco De Natale - Full Professor University of Trento - francesco.denatale@unitn.it Duc-Tien Dang-Nguyen Assoc. Professor University of Bergen - ductien.dangnguyen@uib.no